Guide to the Oral History of the American Left: Radical Histories Collection OH 002
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Louise Thompson Patterson Description: Youth in Sacramento; Scottsboro case in 1930s., Nov 16, 1981-Nov 30, 1981 (Cd Access OH-02-061 to OH-02-065, Cd ohaloh020059b1p1 / ohaloh020059b1p2, Cd ohaloh020060b1p3 / ohaloh020060b1p4, Cd ohaloh020061b1p5 / ohaloh020061b1p6, Cassette 185, Cd ohaloh020062b1p7 / ohaloh020062b1p8, Cd ohaloh020063b1p9)
- Pearl, Feb. 22, 1982 (Cassette 296, Cd ohaloh200135b1p1 / ohaloh200135b1p2, Cd ohaloh200136b1p3 / ohaloh200136b1p4)
- Albert Perocco Description: Bridgeport (Connecticut) Socialist Party; Jasper McLevy as Socialist Mayor; 1960s., Jan 19, 1968 (Cassette Trancript only)
- Elaine Perry Description: Women's role in WWII electrical industry; National Negro Congress; UE vs IUE; reflections., Mar 26, 1979 (Cassette 187A-B)
- Irja M. Peters Description: Finnish-American left of the 1930s in Mesabi Range., Jul 30, 1983 (Cassette 188A-B)
- Sam Pevzner Description: Pennsylvania IWO; activities within sphere of the Yiddishe Kultur Farband., Jun 26, 1983 (Cassette 189)
- Utah Phillips Description: IWW folk singer recalling experiences from 1940s to present, on WBJC (Baltimore) radio broadcast., undated (Cassette 190)
- Marge Piercy, April 1979 (Cassette 297)
- Rose Podmaka Description: United Electrical Workers-Hatfield Wire and Cable; UE and the Association of Catholic Trade Unionists; 1940s., Jan 22, 1979-Mar 19, 1979 (Cd Access OH-02-066 / OH-02-067, Cassette 191, Cd ohaloh020064p1 / ohaloh020064p2, Cd ohaloh020065)
- Justine Pollier Description: Origins of National Lawyers' Guild; 1930s., Jun 22, 1982 (Cassette 192)
- Popular Front Culture Description: Discussion led by Paul Buhle, includes A.B. Magil, Steve Max, Steve Nelson, Nat Cohen and others, about the meaning of "culture" to younger generation in the Popular Front; attitudes toward sports, particularly baseball in Left and in the Daily Worker., Dec 3, 1977 (Cassette 193A-C)
- Pearl Zeluck Porterfield Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency, Workers Party 1940s, May 7, 1983 (Cassette 194)
- Collection of Lectures Description: Lectures by Albert Prago, John Gerassi, Carl Marzani, Dante Puzzo, David Rabinowitz, Murray Solow, Carl Geiser; songs of the Spanish Civil War by Pete Seeger., Oct 20, 1981-Dec 8, 1981 (Cassette 195A-M)
- Albert Prago, March 20, 1991 (Cassette 311A-B)
- William Preston Description: University of Wisconsin; impact of William Appleman Williams; Industrial Workers of the World; experiences as a historian., Aug 10, 1983 (Cassette 197A-B)
- Timo Puropudas Description: Ethnic press; Editor of Tyomies, Finnish., Jul 31, 1983 (Cassette 196A-B)
  No Access Cassette for 196B / Master only
- Sam Pevzner, Sept. 24, 1978 (Cassette 403)
- Paul Andreas Rasmussen Description: Illinois Socialist Party and Workers Alliance, formation of Socialist Workers Party; 1930s-1940s., Apr 3, 1984, 1972 (Cassette 198)
- George Rawick Description: YCL and Wallace movement, Shachtmanite movement and the new left., Oct 4, 1984 (Cassette 199A-B, Cd OH-02-199A / OH-02-199B)
- Philip Raymond Description: Auto Workers Union; ethnic communities of auto workers; 1920s-1930s., Oct 22, 1982 (Cassette 200A-B)
- Rose Raynes Description: Emma Larazus Federation, International Workers Order, 1930s., Mar 21, 1979 (Cassette 201)
- Paul Richards Description: Communist Party Madison WI; student Left; reflections., Nov 5, 1983 (Cassette 204)
- Ernie Reymer, Feb. 16, 1978 (Cassette 404A-B)
- Harvey Richards Description: Radical film-making; work with SNCC and use of film as educational/ fundraising tool; 1960s., Nov 5, 1983 (Cassette 203A-B)
  No transcript or index available
- George and Al Ribak Description: Recollections of two long-time former Socialist Party activists; 1910-1940s., Apr 1, 1967 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Minnie Rivkin Description: Yiddish Chorus; Yiddishkayt; 1930-1980., Apr 7, 1980 (Cassette 205)
- Lester Rodney Description: Radicalism; sportswriting for the Daily Worker, from 1930s; sports during the Cold War., Dec 29, 1981 (Cassette Index only)
- I.A. Ronch Description: Political cultural life in Allerton Avenue Coops, Bronx; Yiddish-speaking sector of Communist Party; leader of Jewish People's Chorus; c. 1950s-1970s., Apr 14, 1981 (Cd ohaloh020069b1p7 / ohaloh020069b1p8, Cd ohaloh020070b1p1 / ohaloh020070b1p2, Cd ohaloh020071b1p3, Cd ohaloh020066b1p1 / ohaloh020066b1p2, Cd ohaloh020067b1p3 / ohaloh020067b1p4, Cd ohaloh020068b1/p5 / ohaloh020068b1p6, Cd Access OH-02-68 / OH-02-69 / OH-02-70, Cd Access OH-02-71 / OH-02-72, Cassette 207)
  Transcript Available, Box 2 and Index available
- Karen & Jack Rosenberg, N.D. (Cassette 331A-D)
- Nina Rosenberg Description: Yiddish cultural movement, Miami Beach, since 1940s., Mar 14, 1983 (Cd Access OH-O2-075 / OH-O2-076 / OH-O2-077 / OH-O2-078, Cd ohaloh020072b1p1 / ohaloh020072b1p2, Cd ohaloh020073b1p3 / ohaloh020073b1p4, Cd ohaloh020074b1p5 / ohaloh020074bb1p6, Cd ohaloh020075b1p7, Cassette 208)
  master cassettes only
- Sadie Rosenberg Description: International Workers Order, Trade Union Unity League, Young Communist League, United Electrical Workers Local 427- Solar Manufacturing Co., c. 1930s-1940s., Jan 11, 1979-Jan 15, 1979 (Cd ohaloh020079b1p3 / ohaloh020079b1p4, Cassette 209, Cd Access OH-02-079 / OH-02-080 / OH-02-081 / OH-02-082, Cd OH-02-083, Cd ohaloh020076b1p1 / ohaloh020076b1p2, Cd ohaloh020077b1p3 / ohaloh020077b1p4, Cd ohaloh020078b1p1 / ohaloh020078b1p2)
  master cassette only
- Paul Rosencrantz Description: Communist Party, National Maritime Union, factory organizing in New York and in Maine., Jan 15, 1981 (Cd ohaloh0200094b1p1 / ohaloh0200094b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200095b1p3, Cassette 210)
- Florence Rossie Description: Hunter College Socialist Party; Socialist Party, 1930s., Mar 17, 1982 (Cassette 211)
- Dan Rubel Description: Jefferson School of Social Science; Cold War., Apr 12, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Annette Rubenstein Description: Joining the Communist Party; American Labor Party activities; Mike Quill; Jefferson School., December 18, 1980 (Cd ohaloh020084p1 / ohaloh020084p2, Cd Access OH-02-088, Cassette 214)
- Annette Rubenstein Description: American Labor Party; day care and birth control information campaigning; School for Democracy and Jefferson School, 1940s-1950s., Octover 17, 1976 (Cd ohaloh020080p1 / ohaloh020080p2, Cd ohaloh020081p3 / ohaloh020081p4, Cd ohaloh020082p5 / ohaloh020082p6, Cassette 213, Cd Access OH-02-084 / OH-02-085 / OH-02-086, Cd OH-02-087, Cd ohaloh020083p1 / ohaloh020083p2, Cd ohaloh020084p1 / ohaloh020084p2)
- Annette Rubenstein, March 9, 1993 (Cassette 326)
- Joe Rudiak Description: Union activities and Left affiliation; electoral campaign and red-baiting, 1930s., Jun 28, 1983
- Joe Rudiak & Peter Muselin & Bernard Luketich Description: Croatian Fraternal Union; 1930s-50s., Jun 8, 1983
- Julia Ruuttila Description: Industrial Workers of the World, Oregon and Washington, 1910s., Sep 7, 1972 (Cassette Transcript only)
- William Santora Description: Early life in Jersey City, work at Emerson Radio N.Y., United Electrical Workers staff member helped organize Fed. Tel. and Tel., Westinghouse Elevator Co., N.J., influence of the left., Jul 24, 1980 (Cassette 218A-B)
- Sophie Saroff Description: Family background in Russia, 1905 Revolution; Rand School, ILGWU and Camp Unity; 1930s International Labor Defense., Dec 14, 1979 (Cassette 219A-E)
- Sophie Saroff Description: Recording of 80th b-day party, May 15, 1979 (Cd ohaloh0200144b1p1 / ohaloh0200144b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200145b1p3 / ohaloh0200145b1p4, Cassette 144-145)
- Daniel Boone Schirmer Description: National Students' League, CIO & students, Mar 18, 1981 (Cassette 221A-B)
- Charles Schwartz Description: Background in Fall River, 1950s-1960s; high school radicalization on; life and politics in Madison, late 1960s; down and out in California; return to New England, activities in Left, 1970s-1980s., Apr 21, 1984 (Cassette 222A-B)
- Chaym Schwartz Description: Activity as Yiddish poet in Yiddish Cultural circles, 1930s-present., Dec 29, 1981 (Cassette 223)
- Pete Seeger Description: Use of music as social protest; growing up in 1930s with folk music; Communist Party song book; war and prison sentence; sense of humor and curiosity; songs on Scottosboro and International Labor Defense., Feb 25, 1981 (Cassette 224A-B)
- Bernard Segal Description: Workman' Circle, Providence, R.I., 1920s-40s; ethnic socialist groups in Providence; Socialists and Communists., May 4, 1977 (Cassette 225)
- Bernard Segal Description: no description currently available, July 14, 1992 (Cd OH-02-143, Cassette 412, Cd ohaloh0200143p1 / ohaloh0200143p2)
- Edith Segal Description: Music and dance and the Left in the 1930s., Feb 7, 1981 (Cassette 226, Cd ohaloh0200141p1 / ohaloh0200141p2, Cd Access OH-02-141)
- Irving Seid Description: New York background; Depression and Unemployed Councils; McCarthyism., Jun 4, 1976 (Cassette 227A)
- Tauhma Seid Description: Youth in Yorkville section of New York, 1920s; cafeteria workers unionism; Young Communist League; Communist Party, 1940s-50s., Jun 4, 1976 (Cassette 227B)
- Leo Seidlitz Description: Brooklyn College radical politics, mid-1930s; Trotskyism, late 1930s; Workers Party, 1940s, and later influence of Max Shachtman., Jul 20, 1983 (Cassette 229, 229.5, Cd Access OH-02-97, Cd ohaloh200097b2, Cd ohaloh200137b1p1 / ohaloh200137b1p2, Cd ohaloh200138b1p3 / ohaloh200138b1p4)
- Nina Serrano Description: Bohemian observations of middle-American Madison in 1950s; recruitment into Youth Labor League; activities in founding of the Peace Center; travel to Peace Festival, Moscow and to China; subsequent difficulty in school, Madison; maintaining contact with former Madison friends., Nov 16, 1983 (Cassette 230)
- Mark Sharron Description: Workers Party, Trotskyism, Workers' Party, Max Shachtman, 1930s-1950s., May 5, 1983 (Cassette 231A-B)
- Mark Sharron Description: Russian background; Brownsville childhood; City College of New York and Young Communist League; Trotskyism; European experiences; Workers Party and World War II., Aug 19, 1983 (Cd ohaloh0200096b1p1 / ohaloh0200096b1p2, Cassette 232)
- Mark Sharron Description: Activity in the Trotskyist movement of the 1930s-40s; Trotskyism and international questions; character of the Workers Party., Nov 10, 1983 (Cd 0haloh0200098p1 / ohaloh0200098p2, Cassette 233)
- John Shenton Description: Socialist Party, Bridgeport, Conn., 1920-60., Jun 20, 1967 (Cassette Transcipt only)
- Anne Shore Description: Communist Party; United office and Professional Workers of America (UOPWA); picketing of the Nazi ship Bremen; Detroit, 1940s; Civil Rights Congress and Progressive Party, Los Angeles, late 1940s-early 1950s; effects of McCarthy period; work for 1199 (Hospital Workers), 1960s., May 31, 1982-Jun 15, 1982 (Cassette 235A-H)
- Meyer Shticker Description: no description currently available., N.D. (Cassette 405)
- Elias Shulman Description no description currently available., Oct. 19, 1982 (Cassette 300)
- Leo Sidlitz Description: no description currently available., Aug. 22 1983 (Cassette 353)
- Robert J. Silverstein & Howard Meyers Description: International Labor Defense, National Lawyers Guild 1930s-40s, Jun 22, 1982 (Cassette 236A-B)
- Fanny S. Simon Description: Socialist Party 1930s, Feb 12, 1982 (Cassette 237A-B)
- Donald Slaiman Description: no description currently available., Dec. 16, 1994 (Cassette 341)
- Jessie Taft Smith Description: Family background in Norwalk, Connecticut, 1910s-1920s; Young Communist League, laundry workers' union, social and political life, 1930s., Nov 19, 1981 (Cassette 238A-B)
- Name: Soble, Richard Description: Radical legal work in Detroit, 1960s-70s, including "Red Squad" lawsuit, late 1960s rent strike., Mar 31, 1983 (Cassette 239)
- Socialist Labor Party Description: Socialist Labor Party "South Slavonian" language federation, 1920s-50s, Detroit and Cleveland., Mar 17, 1983 (Cassette 240A-D)
- Southern Negro Youth Congress Description: Forum on its history, with one-time SNYC activists Henry Winston, James Jackson, Grace Tillman Bassett, Esther Jackson, and Dorothy Burnham., Feb 6, 1984 (Cd ohaloh0200108b1p1 / ohaloh0200108b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200109b1p3 / ohaloh0200109b1p4, Cassette 241)
- Anton Srok Description: Activities in Milwaukee Croatian Fraternal Union, 1930s-present; labor activities in Milwaukee during 1930s; theatrical activities of interviewee, a prominent amateur Croatian-American actor in Milwaukee., Jul 26, 1983 (Cd ohaloh0200100b1p1 / ohaloh0200100b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200101b1p3, Cassette 242)
- Anna Srunsky-Walling Description: no description currently available., July 17, 1960 (Cassette 292A-C)
- Morton Stavis Description: (cassette A) childhood in the Lower East Side 1915-, education in yeshivah, CCNY 1930s, joining Social Security Administration, unionism and civil rights. (cassette B) Social Securit Act, working with Senator Wagner; (cassette C) War Labor Board, voting rights in Mississippi 1965, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Carl and Anne Braden; (cassette D) work with the Center for Constitutional Rights, civil rights cases: McSurley Case 1967, Philippines Case 1986., Jan. 20, 1990 - Feb 7, 1991 (Cassette 314A-D)
- Sid Sterin & Eugene Dennis Description: Speech of Sid Stein in debate with Eugene Dennis at CPUSA Executive Committee, Dec 1957 (Cassette 325)
- Charlotte Stern Description: no description currently available., May 7, 1979 (Cassette 330A-B)
- Sholem Stern Description: Radical Yiddish writer and poet, Montreal and New York, 1920s-30s., Sep 18, 1978 (Cassette 243, Cd ohaloh0200102p1 / ohaloh0200102p2)
- Sholem Stern Description: no description currently available (Cassette 406)
- Isidor Steuzert Description: The Jewish Socialist Federation, American Communism, the Lovestoneites., Oct 27, 1982 (Cd ohaloh0200103p1, Cassette 244)
- Chambers Stewart Description: no description currently available., June 22, 1983 (Cassette 382)
- Hayam Suller Description: Background in Jewish progressive movement; problems of the Morgen Freiheit today., Jan 20, 1983 (Cd ohaloh0200104p1 / ohaloh0200104p2, Cassette 245)
- Arne Swabeck Description: Large collections of interviews taken in the 1970s, Apr 7, 1975-Apr 11, 1975 (Cassette 246A-WW)
- Arne Swabeck Description: Scandinavian Socialist Federation and press, Oct 23, 1982 (Cd ohaloh200105b1p1 / ohaloh200105b1p2, Cd ohaloh200106b1p3 / ohaloh200106bap4, Cassette 246)
  Transcript available, Box 2 and Index available
- A.O Syrstad. Description: Workers Party, Independent Socialist League, Seattle, Washington, 1940s-1950s., Jan 5, 1978 (Cd ohaloh0200107p1, Cassette 247)
- Loretta Szeliga Description: no description currently available., Dec. 8, 1981 (Carton 354)
- Moishe Shik Description: no description currently available., 1982-12-27 (Cassette 234, Cd ohaloh0200099p1 / ohaloh0200099p2)
- Anna Taffler Description: Unemployed Council Brooklyn 1930-1934, Jan 5, 1978 (Cassette 248A-B)
- Stephen Tendler, Oct. 5, 1984 (Cassette 411)
- Norman Thomas Description: Reminiscences, 1960 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Norman Thomas Description: Recollections of Jasper McLevy, Socialist Mayor of Bridgeport, Conn., 1933-1957., Nov 17, 1966 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Norman Thomas: 1932 Campaign, 50th anniversary Description: Various speakers including Ruth Senior, Mickey Most, Herb Wolfe, John Herling, Noah Walter, Michael Harrington; recollections of Thomas' first presidential campaign and his overall career and influence., Nov 19, 1982-Nov 20, 1982 (Cassette 251A-F)
  Transcript availalbe, Box 2 and index available
- Bessie Thomashow Description: Workmen's Circle, 1930s, undated (Cassette 253)
- Fred Thompson Description: Nature of language federations attached to Industrial Workers of the World; language federations and ethnic press in IWW., Jul 26, 1983 (Cassette 254-255, Cd ohaloh0200116b1p1 / ohaloh0200116b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200117b1p3, Cd ohaloh0200118p1 / ohaloh0200118p2)
- Alan Thomson, Feb 11, 1993 (Cassette 327A-B)
- Ahrne Thorne Description: Polish background; education of an anarchist; Yiddish anarchism in the US since the 1920s; Yiddish anarchism and Zionism; Rudolf Rocker., Jan 22, 1983 (Cassette 256A-B)
  tape#: 1 U2CC
- Ahrne Thorne, N.D. (Cassette 407)
- Frank Trager (Cassette 338)
- Haunani-Kay Trask, N.D. (Cassette 303A-B)
- Esther Travaglio Description: Activity of "Gene" Travaglio, anarchist activist and job-printer in Seattle and in California; background and activities of Esther Hartz Travaglio., Oct 30, 1982 (Cassette 257, Cd ohaloh200110b1p1 / ohaloh200110b1p2, Cd ohaloh200111b1p3)
- Jerry Trauber, Nov. 4, 1979 (Cassette 408)
- Uhro Tuuomien Description: Activity of "younger" generation of Finnish-American radicals, Nov 5, 1983 (Cd ohaloh200112p1 / ohaloh200112p2, Cassette 258)
- Jean Tussey Description: Steel Workers Organizing Committee, Sociallist Party, and Socialist Workers Party in New Jersey and Southern California, 1930s-early 1940s., Oct 24, 1978-Oct 25, 1978, Mar 20, 1979 (Cassette 259, Cd ohaloh0200113b1p1 / ohaloh0200113b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200114b1p3 / ohaloh0200114b1p4, Cd ohaloh0200115b1p5 / ohaloh0200115b1p6)
- Gus Tyler, Oct. 29, 1973 (Carton 339A-B)
- Apr 30, 1983 (Cassette 261A-B)
- Unidentified Ukrainian Poet, March 21, 1979 (Cassette 390)
- Name: Willard Uphaus and Ruth MacLennan Description: Religion-political activity, friendship with Claude Williams, c. 1930s., Jul 20, 1983 (Cassette 262A-B)
- Vittorio Vidali Description: Italian Language Federation, American Communist movement, 1920s; translated from his autobiography., Aug 6, 1981 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Abraham Vishnu & Getzel Becker Description: radicalism and culture in New York and Miami Beach; anti-semitism in radical movements of Poland; life for Jewish workers in pre-revolutionary Cuba; importance of Yiddish culture for political movements, 1920s-1950s., Oct 25, 1978 (Cassette 264, Cd ohaloh200119b1p1 / ohaloh200119b1p2)
- Frank Wallin Description: Editorial activities for Tyomies and Industrilistii, Finnish-American IWW newspaper; life of a Finnish-American radical newspaperman, 1940s-1970s., Jul 31, 1983 (Box 2)
- Hershel Walker, N.D. (Cassette 356-357)
- Bjong Violet Wainio, Jul 17, 1984 (Cassette 265)
- Jacob Waisbord, June 28, 1993 (Cassette 340A-B)
- Albert Warner, May 3, 1980 (Cassette 305A-B)
- Susan Warren Description: Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy; Jefferson School of Social Science, 1950s., Apr 17, 1966 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Arthur Waskow Description: Students for a Democratic Society, Apr 2, 1970 (Cassette no tape)
- Stan Weir Description: C.L.R. James and Johnson-Forest Tendency, Workers Party, Oct 22, 1982 (Cassette 269A-M)
- Sam Weiss Description: Role of the Freie Arbeter Shtimme (Free Voice of Labor) in the labor movement of the 1920s-1930s; anarchists within Arbeter Ring., Apr 8, 1980 (Cassette 271)
- Louis Weiss, March 15, 1983 (Cassette 384A-B)
- Saul Wellman Description: Communists & United Auto Workers during WWII, Hitler-Stalin pact, cold war and Left, Aug 24, 1972 (Cassette Index Only)
  No tape
- Myra Tanner Weiss Description: Unemployed movement and Trotskyist movement; anti-fascist demonstrations; experiences as Socialist Workers Party candidate; c. 1920s-1950s., 1982 (Cd Access OH-02-142, Cassette 270, Cd ohaloh0200142p1 / ohaloh0200142p2)
- Saul Wellman: 65th birthday dinner, 1980 (Cassette 273, Cd ohaloh200122b1p1 / ohaloh200122b1p2, Cd ohaloh200123b1p3 / ohaloh200123b1p4)
- Ed Wiese Description: Westinghouse Elevator Plant, Jersey City; President, Local 456; U.E., 1981 (Cassette 274A-B)
- Yvette West Description: youth in IWW, mid-1930s; father (Yiddish critic B. Rivkin), his literary career., Jan 19, 1983 (Cassette 275A-B, Cd OH-02-275A side A / OH-02-275A side B / OH-02-275B side A)
- Jim Williams Description: Students for a Democratic society 1960s, Apr 2, 1970 (Cassette 276)
- Paul W. Williams Description: Prosecution of International Workers' Order 1950s, May 11, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Tim Wohlforth Description: Bridgeport, Connecticut; Socialism and Trotskyism; c. 1930s- 1950s., Aug 29, 1976 (Cassette Transcript only)
- Alice Dodge Wolfson Description: League for Industrial Democracy, Office Workers Union, New England CIO and Socialist Party, 1930s., Apr 1, 1982 (Cassette 279)
- Workers Party/Standing Fast Conference Description: Commemorating the opening of the Max Shachtman Papers at the Tamiment Library; panel presentations on 1) the character and activities of the Workers Party, 1940-49 2) Harvey Swados' novel Standing Fast, based on the WP, and 3) three magazines with roots in the WP, Politics, Dissent, and New Politics. Speakers include Herman Benson, Ricky Flanders, Albert Glotzer, Julius Jacobson, Irving Sanes, Morton Clurman, Paul Cowan, Lewis Coser, Robert Cummings, Phyllis Jacobson., May 6, 1983-May 7, 1983 (Cassette 280A-H)
- Frederick Wright Description: Work as a clip- joint musician and freelance cartoonist for NMU; Cold War and shift to UE News; c. 1920s-1940s., Jun 20, 1984 (Cassette 281)
- Fanny Yellin Description: Anarchist circle in Philadelphia, 1910s; Rudolf Rocker and role of the Rocker Circle., Apr 16, 1980 (Cassette 282)
- Karl Yoneda Description: Japanese-American Communist movement; Japanese-language press; role in labor movement and opposition to internment camps; Popular Front in Japanese-American Left c1920s-1940s., Jan 7, 1983 (Cassette 283)
- Vincent Young Description: Congress of Radical Equality, Brooklyn; Downstate Medical Center, New York World's Fair demonstrations; CORE conventions and campaigns; c. 1940s-1960s., Aug 4, 1983 (Cassette 244-246, Cd ohaloh020244b1p1 / ohaloh020244b1p2, Cd ohaloh020245b1p3 /ohaloh020245b1p3, Cd ohaloh020246n1p5 / ohaloh020246n1p6)
  No Access Cassette 284C / Master only
- Meyer Zackheim Description: New York Left in 1910s-20s; problems of Jewish progressive movement in Miami Beach, 1970s., Oct 24, 1978 (Cassette 286.5, Cd ohaloh200128p1)
- Zackheim, Glassmans, Klieger, Rosenfeld (Group #III) Description: New York Progressive Yiddish activity in 1920s-40s; immigration and trade union; role of progressive movement in Miami Beach Jewish community, 1970s., Oct 24, 1978 (Cd ohaloh200126b1p1 / ohaloh200126b1p2, Cd ohaloh200127b1p3 / ohaloh200127b1p4, Cassette 286)
- Meyer Zackheim, Archie Rothenberg & Rose Lipshitz Description: Problems of immigrant women (Rose Lipshitz) in America of 1920s and appeal of the Left; political activities of Jewish Left in 1920s-30s (Rothenberg); YKUF reading circles., Oct 24, 1978 (Cassette 287.5, Cd ohaloh200131p1 / ohaloh200131p2)
- Mary Zacheim, Oct. 24, 1978 (Cd ohaloh200124b1p1 / ohaloh200124b1p2, Cd ohaloh200125b1p3 / ohaloh200125b1p4, Cassette 285)
- Meyer Zackheim, Ed Weiss, Silvers (group #I ), October 23, 1978 (Cassette 287, Cd ohaloh0200129b1p1 / ohaloh0200129b1p2, Cd ohaloh0200130b1p3 / ohaloh0200130b1p3)
- Joseph Zawadowski Description: Polish-American Left in Chicago; Spanish Civil War experiences; c.1920s-1970s., Jul 28, 1983 (Cassette 288, Cd ohaloh200132b1p1 / ohaloh200132b1p2, Cd ohaloh200133b1p3 / ohaloh200133b1p4)
- Steve Zeluck Description: Johnson-Forest Tendency; Trotskyist movement, Philadephia and Chicago; reflections on C.L.R. James., Dec 15, 1982 (Cassette 289, Cd ohaloh200134p1 / ohaloh200134p2)
- Steve Zeluck, N.D. (Cassette 410)
- Charles Zimmerma n, Oct 31, 1974 (Cassette 290, Cd ohaloh020085b1p1 / ohaloh020085b1p2, Cd ohaloh020086b1p3 / ohaloh020086b1p4, Cd Access OH-02-089 / OH-02-90)
  International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, struggle between left and right, 1910s-1920s.
- Celia Lewis Zitron Description: New York Teachers Union, 1940s, May 8, 1976